26 season. First day of camp for the
Chargers is July 23rd in Elsagundo. The
Rams open camp on July 25th at Lola
Marry Mount. The first day of the Rams
camp could have some drama. There's been
a lot of chatter in recent weeks that
defensive lineman Aaron Donald is giving
serious thought to coming out of
retirement. The 35-year-old Donald
retired in 2024. Donald, a three-time
defensive player of the year, is the
Rams all-time sacks leader with 111.
Stay tuned on that. Tonight at 6, it's
your Friday night sports pick. Out of
bounds and prime time. Join me and my
co-host Neil Scar Bro for 60 minutes of
sports chatter with some black folks
flavor. You can hang out with us on the
KBLA YouTube channel or hit us up at
1800-920-1580.
No debates, no speculation, just the
info you need. That's your KBLA Sports
Minute. I'm Ray Richardson on KBLA Talk
1580.
You can't fix what you won't face
>> and we face it every day.
>> This is KBLA talk 1580.
>> Another thing is to disseminate
propaganda to influence people's minds
and this is a major function of the CIA.
>> [music]
[music]
>> They saw [music] the
>> [cheering]
>> What's good everybody?
Welcome to the first ever episode of the
summer of seals here on KBLA Talk Radio
1580. I am very happy to be spending my
summer with you good people. And uh
shout out to Tavis for bringing me in
and and and putting me on the radio
waves once again. Uh for those who don't
know, I have been doing radio for a
really long time. Like I started doing
radio when I was right out of college.
Like it was literally my first job out
of college at Serious Satellite Radio
back in 20
I can't it wasn't even 20 yet. It was
just 2000. So back in 2003
and so I was doing radio there for a
while and um then fast forward I ended
up back on radio when I was doing my
show the Amanda Seal show and now here
we are with Summer of Seals. And so I
get to join you guys every Friday uh 12
to 2:00 p.m. Pacific and 4 to 6:00 p.m.
Pacific. So, shout out to everybody who
downloaded the app just cuz they heard
that I WAS COMING THROUGH. OKAY?
appreciate the love and appreciate just,
you know, the excitement about my voice
and my point of view because I want
y'all to know just off rip that my voice
and my point of view are really here as
a vessel in purpose for uplifting the
people, for decolonizing minds, for
bringing us forward uh in our energy
work, in our intentionality, in our just
regaining power over ourselves because
we have really been disempowered. And I
don't just mean black folks, but I
especially mean black folks, if you feel
me. [laughter] So, I am really happy to
be here. Also, I just think like the
radio
like the radio just still has its weight
because let me tell you, if anything go
down digital, etc., etc., etc., them
radio waves, they be riding. That's why
everybody needs to have a crank radio.
Okay, that's why because the radio waves
are still out here doing their thing
even when the Wi-Fi and the fiber optics
and the data centers get OD. By the way,
I just found out that they are building
a data center around my way. And I am
not happy about it. And you know the
reason why the data center is so
basically they built the data center and
then now they're slowing they they like
were going to expand it but now they had
to stop because of Eagles. Did y'all
know that eagles are so protected in the
United States that you can't even have
an eagle feather? Like if you find an
eagle feather on the ground, apparently
it's like illegal for you to have the
eagle feather, which I think is nuts.
However, like cuz like the rules that
they come up with in this place are so
wild cuz like it's illegal for you to
have an eagle feather, but no one's been
arrested from the Epstein files. What
are we talking about?
Okay.
Also, like how do they find out that you
have the eagle feather? Is it because
you're trying to sell the eagle feather?
Are you wearing the eagle feather like
in your hair? Like what? And then who
rolls up on you to say, "Yo, is that a
eagle feather?" I mean, honestly, the
way these cops be acting, they they
might they might. I saw a video of a
brother in Connecticut who called the
cops because he was streaming and he was
attacked while he was streaming and the
cops rolled up on him and he was like,
"I called the cops. I called y'all." And
they proceeded to pat him down and then
illegally search his bag on camera. And
you're just like,
it really don't never stop. Do it. No,
it doesn't. and it's not going to stop
anytime soon. So, let's just understand
that that is the point of view that I'm
speaking from at all times on this here
show that it hasn't stopped. It never
stopped and it's not going to stop until
we change how we are addressing it.
Because drastic change does not take
place without drastic change and we've
been doing the same god dang thing over
and over and over again since the civil
rights movement. We keep seeming to
think that we just going to keep voting
our way out of nonsense, voting our way
out of evil. We think that that's all we
have to do. We think if we make enough
money and we keep being shown over and
over again that that's just simply not
the way. Now, I realized that uh I was
like caught in the matrix of things
after October 7th and seeing the way
that the media was completely me
misrepresenting and just lying to my
face. seeing the way that the Democrats
are misrepresenting and this lying to my
face about what I was seeing
Palestinians document themselves with
their cameras in real time and it was
just so blatantly obvious and it just
shook up the world. I mean like Alien
63, it shook up my world. And after
that, I realized like I I really I
really need to reassess like what I'm
believing in and and what my perception
of of things is. And shortly after that,
my support of Palestine had me um
basically blacklisted and folks were
canceling my standup shows. And it was a
really tough time that forced me to take
a real good look at like who I am, where
I am, and where I'm at. And at the time,
who I was was somebody in Hollywood that
had a really big heart, a really big
mind, but that always was bumping heads
with folks. Um, where I was, like I
said, in Hollywood, and where I'm at was
in the wrong place. That's why I was
bumping head with folks because I don't
belong in a space that runs on greed and
opportunism and fakeness [laughter]
because I am everything but those
things. So, it feels really good to have
found my way um through my own way,
which is why like I just put out a music
album um and you heard one of the songs
uh when we came in. You heard scop and
you're going to hear more songs as I'm
doing this show because I want y'all to
to listen to this music because I didn't
make this music just for something to
bop to. I made it so that you had
something to bop to that you could learn
with because music really is the best
way to get to us because our bodies are
built on rhythm. So my album truth
translator I'm on the cover holding a
kotlas which is what we in Grenada
called a machet call a machete. For
those who don't know, I am I come from
Grenadian descent in the Caribbean as
well as black American descent here in
the States. My father is from uh
Roxbury, Boston. My mother is from
Grenada. And that cudas on the cover is
all about the fact that you use the
cudless to cut a path through the bush.
But then you may also have to cut some
heads. [laughter]
[crying] Okay? [screaming]
You may have to cut some heads. So,
that's what we're doing. Uh, today I'll
be talking about Jay-Z being a sellout.
I'll be talking about this Nolan Wells
case. I'll also be telling you a little
story about why I can't never be invited
nowhere. [snorts] Um, we're also going
to talk about a Regaton case that y'all
may not know about. And I'm of course
going to share how Black I feel today,
hit you with a critical thinking
exercise and a public sees announcement.
So, we'll be here when we come forward
at [music] the Summer of Seals.
The conversation you didn't know you
were waiting for. Amanda Seals. Only on
KBLA Talk. 1580. 1580. 1580. 150.
>> Are you drowning in IRS tax debt? Angela
was. She called Civic Tax Relief and
saved over $80,000. Felicia was having
health problems. Got behind on her
taxes. Interest and penalties were
adding up. She called Civic Tax Relief
and saved over $15,000. Civic Tax Relief
is a professional tax negotiation firm
that can protect you from the IRS. If
you're getting collection letters, call
Civic Tax Relief [music] for a free
consultation. They will go to work
helping you discover all the relief
programs you may qualify for for free.
James owed the IRS $37,000.
[music and singing] Civic Tax Relief
represented him against the IRS and by
the time everything was completed, he
did not owe the IRS anything. If you are
in trouble with the IRS, call [music]
Civic Tax Relief for your free
consultation now. 8002002257
8002002257. [music]
Get a free consultation and real tax
relief. Call 8002002257.
[music]
8002002257.
[screaming]
>> Real talk, no filter. Amanda Seals on
KBLA Talk 1580.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Why are you so blessed
to be loved
Why your [singing]
capttor? [music]
Why are you so [music and singing]
blessed
to be [music] loved
by all I have done?
Why are you so [music and singing]
>> [music]
>> That right there is my joint. Why are
you so pressed? Off my latest album,
Truth Translator. It's Amanda Seals
here. KBLA talk 1580, Summer of Seals is
going down. [singing]
And uh the reason why I played that song
into this break is because we're gonna
talk about Jay-Z and his recent
freestyle. So, let's get into some Black
News.
[music]
Oh man, Jay-Z. Listen, let me let me
just start by saying I am a hip-hop head
to the fullest. So, let me just start by
saying I'm a hip-hop head to the
fullest. So, when I'm talking about
Jay-Z, you're not hearing someone who is
talking about him from the context of
him being on the NFL or him being
Beyonce's husband. No, you talking about
somebody who knows Reasonable Doubt
front to back. Can't stop by from
drinking my ties with Tatai in Nevada.
Haha. Papa life. Okay. Like I have a
signed copy of Reasonable Doubt. Like
let's just Okay. Some of y'all may not
know my pedigree, but yes, I have known
Jay-Z. I know I've known Jay-Z's music
before he was Hov Hovito, etc., etc. So,
he seeing where he has landed is nuts.
It's nuts because don't get me wrong, I
understand that Jay-Z, you know, he's a
hustler. I mean, he has songs about it.
I'm a hustler. I'm I'm a hustler, right?
Like that was the sample that Cass that
uh Cassidy used. He
was an executive, right? Like he found
his way to Dev Jam to be an executive.
Like, of course, Rockefeller, he was the
the owner of Rockefeller. So, this is
not somebody that has ever hidden that
they are a capitalist.
That being said, there's a point in time
where I feel like folks go from I'm just
going along with what's here to,
yeah, I am now rocking with the
oppressor and I am I feel like I've been
accepted. That's how Bill Cosby got in
his little situation.
So Jay-Z had done a series of shows in
New York and he did a freestyle ac
capella. Now, this is a post locks um
locks comb out ac cappella. And the
reason why I say that is because I feel
like this was even more annoying because
now he's like cut his hair down and he's
back to the clean cut. And it's just
like you're really giving us I am
aligning myself with
the optics and the establishment. I'm
not even looking like I don't belong. I
have conformed. I don't know if they had
like an Illuminati birthday cake for
him, like you know, not an Illuminati
birthday cake, but like I really don't
know if they did like some type of like,
"Okay, we moving to the next level
because he really moved to the next
level when he stood up on that stage ac
cappella so that everybody could hear
them and said, "They say I sold out." I
can't really impersonate. I need Jay.
Pharaoh around. They say I sold out.
Yeah, I did sell out three nights. I
sold Yankee Stadium the hell out. Okay,
so here's the thing.
Yes, that's great that you did sell out
Yankee Stadium, but the reason why we're
saying you sold out is because in that
same rhyme, you talked about
folks boycotting Target but having a
problem with you doing a deal with
Target. And so what I want to talk about
in this segment
is the very real problem with black
folks who are undermining undermining
resistance movements by black folks. I
always say that every experience is a
black experience unless it is antilack.
And we have now moved into the very
muddy murky waters of Jay-Z being
antilack. And I need you all to stay
focused with me because that I know
those words make you prickle, right? I
know some people in their car was like,
"No, not Sean Carter." But let's take a
look at some of the actions and
behaviors. So when they were building
the stadium in Brooklyn, there was a lot
of push back. All right? Because it was
going to disrupt a lot of the housing.
It was going to disrupt jobs. You know,
people love to say it's making us jobs.
It's making us jobs. No, no. It was
disrupting the way that life was
existing. And they they brought Jay-Z in
to like a 1% ownership stake so that he
could be the magical negro to pi piper
black folks across the troubled waters
and let these people do what they was
going to do. So, he is manufacturing
consent. They're literally using him as
a token negro to bring negroes. Like
he's like the negro whisperer, okay? And
he was happy to do it. And when he was
saying that he was a part owner of the
Nets, like it really made people be
like, "Well, dang. I mean, if it's if he
gonna be part owner, then we can't get
in the way. You know, that's a black man
doing his black man thing. We got to
really support that." Only to find out,
my mans, you are one% owner.
that that that that don't sound like you
really on on on par with everybody else.
In his mind though, he said it was it's
as long as he has any type of ownership,
it's black ownership. His words, not
mine. Okay,
let's look at another instance.
Jay-Z
went over to work with the NFL
after all of the tom foolery and racism
with Colin Kaepernick. Now, Colin
Kaepernick was kneeling to bring
attention to police brutality. We know
that police brutality in the United
States has always been absolutely
problematic on a whole genocidal level.
Okay? And the reason why I say a
genocidal level is because there are no
measures to stop it. Police are just out
here, you know, murking brothers with
like hot merking black people like hot
cakes, right? they are getting away with
it with immunity. Uh we see things like
the George Floyd bill just get
presented, but Democrats don't follow
through with nothing because the goal is
never to follow through with anything.
So, it just gets put up there to make
people feel like, "Look at they're doing
something." But at the end of the day,
we don't see any actual measures like
active policy change
to decrease
the incessant amount of police
brutality.
So, if you see that the numbers of harm
are continuing to grow and there's
nothing being done to diminish it, well,
I'm calling that a G-side because it's a
specific group that is being implement
that is being sorry, it's a specific
group that's being impacted in a violent
fashion that is often fatal.
So to me, I I don't know about nobody
else, but to me, if I see a brother
putting his career on the line for that,
I'mma stand with that or I'mma stand
back. But what I'm not gonna do is step
over him
and squat up with the same folks that
are standing on him.
That to me is an incredible act of
disloyalty
and antilackness.
And you know, the willingness of folks
to actually overlook that because it's
Jay-Z. Also, like, why do y'all love
Jay-Z so much? Is it really just the
music? Cuz I I mean, listen, I love the
records like anybody else. But y'all I
mean, these people are not infallible.
They rappers. I mean, as somebody who
has had my fair share of a rapper, th
they are topnotch fallible. Okay? They
are highly fallible figures. All right?
You talking to somebody who's was in
music business, has dated rappers. I am
a rapper. though I will say my
fallibility is much slimmer than the
male the male quotient. Um, so when I
when I see these two things, I'm looking
at Jay-Z like, "Wow, like you really are
not down."
And then he had the nerve to call Cap
out in this rap and essentially state
that Colin Kaepernick had signed an NDA
and so he's like quieted, but Jay-Z is
free and he can do what he wants with
the NFL. Well, first of all, according
to Jamal Hill on her podcast with Carrie
Champion, she said that's actually not
true. So, my man's is lying. We're doing
lies. We're not doing fabrications.
No, we're not doing very similitude.
Come on.
Come on. That's not Why are you even
putting Cap's name in your mouth? Like,
you to me that's nuts. To me, to me,
that's nuts. you over there at the NFL
and at the end of the day, I know y'all
love your football, but the truth of the
matter about the NFL is that it's racist
as FL.
Okay? And you can love your football,
but let's just always remember to keep
it a buck. They are looking at the
players as black bucks.
And that's a double entandra because
they're looking at them as black bucks,
meaning black people making them money.
and they looking them at looking at them
as black bucks meaning slaves on the
field. Like we we know that, right? Like
we we understand that. We we know that
the the ownership of NFL the the the
black quotient of ownership in the NFL
is slim to none. I think it might even
might be none.
So then Jay-Z stood on stage and talked
about how folks were hypocrites
for boycotting Target while using Meta
and Google.
And I just I was so
w I was I was honestly wowed
at the um at how at the unmitigated goal
to to to suggest that him a billionaire
undermining a boycott
that came into power or that came into
existence due to targets.
willingness to expune their DEI programs
because that's where the boycott came
from. Okay.
So, his willingness to then undermine
that boycott, which for the record has
been successful
in order to then do a deal with them,
because that's the whole thing. Now,
that you do the deal with them, you're
essentially saying, "I want to be in
partnership to bring black folks back to
business." But you haven't reinstated
DEI. So why should we come back to
Target? Because just because you there?
That don't make no sense.
And so then he's sitting there saying
that y'all are hypocrites for boycotting
Target while still using Meta. Now, did
Meta expunge their DEI? Um, did Meta
expunge their DEI programs? Yes.
However, it is a false equivalency to
suggest that a free app is the same as
going to spend your hard-earned dollars
at a place that is underpaying employees
as well as not considering black people,
brown people at the same level as the
rest of the employees. That's literally
a disingenuous argument and is a straw
man. And what I want y'all to take away
from this is that what you're watching
is someone who thinks they're smarter
than you.
He's literally playing in your face.
That's what he's doing. And that is what
the billionaire class does. They play in
your face. Because at the end of the
day, nothing he's saying
exists from the same realm of relativity
as you. You got to pay bills. You got to
figure out how to go somewhere other
than Target just to hold up this
boycott, even though they basically have
a monopoly. You got to figure out how to
handle gas prices fluctuating insane.
Like, you are tasked with all of these
things that he is not tasked with. And
he has the nerve to suggest that you're
being a hypocrite by at least trying to
do an act of resistance. No, absolutely
not. He has the nerve to suggest that
Cap has a cap on him
after he was trying to do an act of
resistance. What you're listening to is
someone suggesting to you that
resistance is futile.
And as come and coming from an MC who
comes from 90s hiphop, that's nuts.
Because the whole thing about hiphop was
that it in itself is an act of
resistance because in not in when
hip-hop came to be, it was coming out of
a time where economically black folks
was definitely on the lowi. was coming
out of the Bronx, out of burn buildings,
out of slum lords. It was coming out of
the crack era where we know now that
there was an active effort, an active
effort, a concerted effort to flood
black communities with drugs
to help suppress and undermine the
growing black power movement that came
on the other side of the civil rights
movement. We know that.
And so then hip-hop comes around. So a
music based on beats, based on rhythm,
based on lyricism, based on
storytelling, based on us us like
literally speaking our own truths,
whether it's our desires to have wealth,
whether it's our frustrations, whether
it's our experiences in the streets,
etc., etc. Either they don't know, don't
show, or don't care about what's going
on in the hood.
Like that's where hip-hop comes from. So
for a cat who comes out of 90s hip hop
to now all the way here in 2026
be on some y'all's little resistance
movements is is nonsense and you're
hypocrites.
Bro,
people be losing themselves. Let's not
forget that he is also in the Epstein
files. Jay-Z is named in the Epstein
files along with Harvey Weinstein, who
he has done business with very loudly.
He is named in the files for causing
harm to women by sexually assaulting
them. That is how he is named in the
files. It's alleged and it's allegedly,
but it is in the files. This is the same
person who was having dinner with Jared
Kushner and and Ivanka Trump. And y'all
said, "Well, what could he do? He was at
a dinner." I'm telling you right now, if
I'm at a dinner with Jared Kushner and
Ivanka Trump, I'm not sitting there. And
y'all know that that's real because when
you saw me at a dinner with Caitlyn
Jenner, I kept it a buck cuz what are we
doing? And you know what he was doing at
that dinner? I'll tell you what he was
doing. He was there, I guess, like as a
part of this, I don't know, this
organization that's raised his funds for
criminal um for criminal justice.
However, at the end of the day, it ends
up being philanthropy that is used for
tax write-offs.
That's it. It's used for tax write-offs
to continue to do the BS because what he
was actually doing was trying to get
people on board with him to open a
casino. So, just just just keep a
context about these folks because they
don't rock with you the way you rock
with them and we need to shake things up
and rock differently.
Speaking of Rockefeller, [laughter]
let's keep it going y'all. We are going
to come forward and talk about these
Democrats who are mourning a terrible
person right here at the summer of
seals.
>> Come on, you can admit it. She says what
[music] you're thinking. You're locked
in with Amanda Seals.
>> Only on KBLA Talk 1580.
>> You go, girl. Girl,
>> I'm Amber Payton with BIN News. Now,
President Trump says he is declassifying
evidence he claims shows China
interfered in the 2020 election by
accessing millions of US voter files.
[music]
>> That information includes names,
addresses, phone numbers.
>> In a Thursday evening prime time
address, Trump accused the Biden
administration and others in government
of hiding the information. He says the
FBI is investigating a renewed call for
Congress to pass his voter ID bill.
Black Maryland Governor Wes Moore says a
state task force has found rising scams,
fraud, and other barriers affecting
immigrant residents. The group will meet
with communities in the coming months to
identify concerns and improve access to
legal protections and resources.
And rapper Eminem's former wife, Kim
Scott, is facing charges after allegedly
attacking officers who responded to her
Michigan home following a reported
suicide attempt. TMZ says Scott tried to
bite one officer and kicked another
before being arrested. Get BIN news now
on demand 247 on the iHeart Radio app.
>> Think it up is an initiative to activate
[music]
studentpowered teacherled learning
projects. Students and teachers, how can
you spark great learning experiences in
your classrooms today? Join at
thinkitup.org.
>> Is this the
>> This is the KBLA Sports Minute with Ray
Richardson.
>> I'm a bad man.
>> The start of NFL training camps is just
around the corner. All 32 teams are
scheduled to begin preparations next
week for the 2026 season. First day of
camp for the Chargers is July 23rd
[music] in Elsagundo. The Rams open camp
on July 25th at Lyola Marry Mount. The
first day of the Rams camp could have
some drama. There's been a lot of
chatter in recent weeks that defensive
lineman Aaron Donald is giving serious
thought to coming out of retirement. The
35-year-old Donald retired in 2024.
Donald, a three-time defensive player of
the year, is the Rams all-time sacks
leader with 111. [music]
Stay tuned on that. Tonight at 6, it's
your Friday night sports pick. Out of
bounds and prime time. Join me and my
co-host Neil Scar Bro for 60 minutes of
sports chatter with some Black Folks
flavor. You can hang out with us on the
KBLA YouTube channel or hit us up at
1800920-1580.
No debates, no speculation, just the
info you need. That's your KBLA Sports
Minute. I'm Ray Richardson on KBLA Talk
1580.
>> Let's do this.
>> Every vote matters. Every voice counts.
And [music] between now and November,
the decisions made in Washington,
Sacramento, and here at home in Los
Angeles will shape the future of your
family and your community. Don't leave
it to chance, and don't leave it to
guesswork. KBLA Talk 1580 is your source
for the political conversations that
matter most. Real talk, real insight
right here. KBALA Talk 1580. The place
for politics. Politics. Politics.
Politics.
>> Yeah, boy.
>> We hear you. We hear you. We feel you.
>> And we got nothing but love for you.
>> Say what's on your mind and follow the
convo wherever you go. Download the KBLA
app on your phone and never miss a
moment of the allne KBLA Talk 50. We got
a lot to talk about.
Let me put my hard hat on, go back
outside, and see if these
procrastination crunch construction
crews have shown up yet. I'm saving
space for grace. But if these trucks
don't show up soon, well, you already
know.
>> Destination Crrenshaw,
your time is up.
With a KBLA Talk 1580 editorial, I'm
Tavis Smiley. KBLA Talk 1580 and
Bethesda Temple Church invite [music]
residents, churches, businesses, and
community leaders along the Krenshaw
corridor to join a vitally important
community conversation Thursday, July
30th, 6:30 p.m. at Bethesda Temple
Church, 4909 Crrenshaw [music]
Boulevard. For years now, this community
has been living with unkempt promises
and the devastating effects [music] of
the unfinished destination Krenshaw
construction project, leaving residents,
businesses, and churches to deal with
myriad problems, including the loss of
parking, restricted access, traffic
congestion, and a lack of emergency
vehicle access when it matters most. For
years now, Procrastination Crrenshaw has
directly contributed to the loss of
customer revenue for local blackowned
businesses and sadly has forced the
closure of some businesses along this
1.3 mile corridor. For years now,
churches have been experiencing
decreased attendance [music] due to the
elimination of parking and social
service programs for vulnerable fellow
citizens have been altogether halted.
For years now, residents have watched
their quality of life erode, and nothing
has been done about it. If they think
they can get away with treating black
folk like secondass citizens, they
better think again.
>> You better think
about what you're trying to do to me.
This town hall meeting is [music] a
reckoning, a public witness, an
opportunity for impacted community
members to share their experiences
[music]
for the public record as we prepare to
hold those responsible accountable for
this enduring nightmare. So, please join
us [music] Thursday, July 30th, 6:30
p.m. at Bethesda Temple Church, 4909
Krenshaw Boulevard. [music] This town
hall meeting is free and open to the
public, but registration is required at
kbla [music]
1580.com.
With a KBLA talk 1580 editorial, I'm
Tavis Smiley, and as always, we welcome
your [music] feedback.
>> Culture, politics, truth.
>> It's a seal summer
>> with Amanda Seals on KBLA Talk 1580.
Got to be a better way.
And we got to make it.
[music]
And we got to create it.
Got to be a better [music] way.
And we got it.
>> [music]
>> We've been walking this same old road.
Yeah, [music]
we fools.
I know where we went.
It was giving grace to ghouls.
They say the lesser [singing] of two.
>> Welcome, welcome, welcome back y'all. It
is Amanda here at KBLA Talk 1580. Shout
out to everybody who is listening. If
you didn't know, uh you can support my
work further by joining my Patreon.
Patreon is an app that allows you to
support artists with a subscribership.
You get exclusive content, early
content, etc. And um my Patreon's only
$5, but I think what the other part
about my my Patreon that I think is so
special is that the community itself is
topnotch because, you know, I'm a
top-notch broad. [laughter] So, I'm
attracting top-notch people. And so,
we've come together to really form this
community that understands that we have
to constantly be in colonization mode,
that we have to constantly be sharing
each sharing skills with each other. So,
we literally do a weekly Skillshare uh
critical thinking kickback where we
either have someone teach a topic like
about soil or child development or
stress skills, etc., etc. Um, or we talk
about like what's going on in the world
and really just just put our heads
together about what's going on, how we
can find solutions, etc. So, consider
joining Patreon, the SEAL Squad. Go to
Patreon, P A T R E O N.comals,
and join up. All right, so that song
that you just heard, Better Way, is off
of my album, Truth Translator. Go to uh
Amandausic.com
or you can go to amanda seals.com to get
Truth Translator. I mean, you can listen
to it on all the streaming. I'm just
saying if you if you're like, "But I
want to give you some bread." I mean,
who says that? But if you're saying that
you can go to amanda.bancamp.com
and skip the corporate middleman and you
know pay anything you want for the album
and listen to it for free. That song
better way is about the fact that
there's got to be a better way than this
current lie of a bipartisan system here
in the United States. You know we have
been under a a a psychological operation
for a long time and part of that has
been to convince us that Democrats and
Republicans are opposing forces. Now,
don't get me wrong, Democrats and
Republicans do behave differently to a
certain extent. And I think that's the
part that we keep getting tripped up on,
right? Because like Republicans are like
very super duper loud with their racism,
with their conservatism, with their uh
economic
um discrimination, etc., etc.,
in a way that makes when Democrats are
doing the same thing look like they're
not doing it.
You feel me? It's like I don't know if
y'all in here are from the 90s, but it's
like remember the [ __ ] Remember the
dance the [ __ ] where you move your head
and your hand right at the same time?
There was levels of the [ __ ] It was on a
spectrum like autism. Nonetheless, it
was still the [ __ ] Like you could either
be like all the way in it
swinging your whole ponytail, right?
Your door knockers knocking your chin,
right? Your hand moving left or right.
Your you got one hand on your thigh.
You're just in the squat. Or you could
just be doing a mini [ __ ]
Just a mini [ __ ] Mini [ __ ] it out. Mini
mini [ __ ] It's still the [ __ ] Okay, you
still dancing. And that is what
Democrats and Republicans are doing.
They're both doing the walk. They're
both dancing
for corporate dollars. They're both
dancing for the central banking system
and the IMF. They're both dancing. And
what I'm hoping to do as we continue to
do this show, we continue to expand our
minds and our consciousness around
what's going on, not just in the United
States, but in the world, is to wake it
up that the longer we support this fake
two-party system and endorse it and
build it up and say the lines that we
like to tell ourselves like, well, we
only have two options. We got to choose
the better of two evils. The longer we
support this, the longer it suppresses
us.
You understand? Because you can't keep
feeding something and then expect it to
die.
Now, maybe you feed if you feeding it
poison, but but y'all ain't trying to do
that though. Okay? And then every time
folks try to do something like, "Okay,
we're going to try and get some
socialists in there." They're like, "Ah,
it's poison." When that's I mean, poison
literally socialist socialism is poison
for capitalism. And then they decided,
well, we'll have democratic socialists,
which is not a socialist at all. But I
digress. This week, we saw the death of
one of the evilst people to ever live,
Lindsey Graham. Let's hear some of the
things Lindsey Graham was saying in his
time on this earth.
>> So, I just want to say I feel good about
the Republican party. I feel good about
where we're going as a nation. We're
killing all the right people and we're
cutting your taxes.
Is there systemic racism in this country
in policing and in other institutions?
>> Uh, no. Not in my opinion. [cheering]
>> Trump is my favorite president. We've
run out of bombs. We didn't run out of
bombs in World War II.
>> Were we wrong to drop an atomic bomb to
end the Japanese reign of terror? Were
we?
>> I'm not with you. I'm with Israel. I
will be is with Israel to our dying day.
>> You just wait for Cuba. Cuba is a
communist dictatorship that's killed
priest and nuns. They've prayed on their
own people. Their days are numbered.
>> America first is to kill people who wish
us ill to take them off the table.
>> When this regime goes down, we're going
to have a new M East. We're going to
make a ton of money. You just wait to
see what comes in the next two weeks.
>> The next two weeks meaning what?
>> We're going to blow the hell out of
these people. The mothership of
international terrorism is about to
collapse.
>> That is Lindsey Graham. That is Lind.
That was that was Lindsey Graham. Now
the the amount of abhorid statements
that he has made um to to me makes it
abundantly clear that like this is not
somebody
who we should be heralding or
remembering
um with fondness. Okay? If we are for
humanism, if we are for elevation, if we
are for opposition,
that's the thing I want to say that like
if if you a Republican, I can of course
you're going to be saying the nonsense
because like he was with what you with.
But we got a whole thing over here,
black folks, where we be thinking that
the Democrats
is with us, right? We we really about
that. And I don't know how someone who's
with me
could listen to all those things that
man said and then tweet this. I am
saddened to learn of the passing of my
former colleague, Senator Lindsey
Graham. He was full of wit, energy, and
charm, and he cared deeply about the
Senate and the people of South Carolina.
Doug and I are sending our thoughts and
our praise to his friends and loved
ones.
Kla Harris tweeted that about that man
that you just heard who sat up there and
said racism doesn't exist in this
country who sat up there and said we're
killing the right people who said Trump
is his favorite president. Now
don't get me wrong I know some of y'all
are like well man you know she's just
being polite. No being polite is
condolences literally the word
condolences.
And I feel like just for extra like
measure. You could misspell it.
Then you got this one. How about this
one? I got to know Senator Lindsey
Graham, traveling with him abroad in
Afghanistan and Ukraine. We had just met
to renew the fight for our big tech
bill. Even though we disagreed on much,
he was always willing to negotiate with
humor and wit. My heart goes out to his
loved ones.
Elizabeth Warren,
you got me. You know what? I don't know
about y'all, but we just ain't cut. We
just not cut the same. I'm not doing all
of that for somebody who has shown that
they are literally a mega mega a
megalomaniac maniac who is actively
against everything that I'm supposedly
fighting for. Unless
unless
I'm not actually fighting for the things
I claim I'm fighting.
Yeah. Right. Like if
If I'm really frightened,
then they're not really my enemy. And
that's why I would say something like
that
because I believe that the Democrats,
not even believe, because it's a fact.
The Democrats are mourning Lindsey
Graham because he was their partner in
crime
because our government is a criminal
organization. Those people in there are
making money off of war, off of insider
trading, off of fraud, and you are out
here trying to figure it out every day.
So when they are sending condolences to
someone like that who wants to see the
world at war, which harms you,
they are not people who care about you.
There's got to be a better way. When we
come forward, I'm gonna tell you why I
never get invited to parties.
Keep it like right here at the summer of
seals.
>> Nothing is off limits. You're listening
to Amanda Seals on KBLA Talk 1580.
>> Yo,
>> point.
>> Hey, you okay? You don't normally miss
those shots.
>> I just haven't been as regular lately
and it's making me feel sluggish.
>> You should try Metamucil. It's been a
game changer for me. Metamucil's
plant-based [music] psyllium fiber helps
trap and remove the waste that weighs
you down.
Ace,
>> you're moving better than you were last
week.
>> Definitely.
>> Metamucil keeps you moving. These
statements have not been evaluated by
the Food and Drug Administration. This
product is not intended to diagnose,
treat, cure, or prevent any disease.
Learn more at metamus.com. [music]
>> This is the story of the one. As a
maintenance engineer at a beverage
manufacturing plant, he starts his day
knowing every line is ready to run
because Gringanger delivers the
industrial-grade products he needs to
keep mixers, conveyors, and packaging
equipment moving. With Granger's fast
selection of bearings, belts, and
motors, he [music] keeps operations
running smoothly so nothing grinds to a
halt. Call 1800 Granger, click
granger.com, or just stop by. Granger,
for the ones who get it done.
Listen up, KBLA delegation. We have
something you need to hear right now.
You may qualify for lowcost home
internet. We're not talking about a
catch. This is real. Many internet
service providers offer lowcost internet
plans if anyone in your household is
enrolled in CalFresh, medical, SSI, or
is income eligible. There are a lot of
families in our community who deserve to
be connected. Here's all you do. Call
844-461-7893.
[music] That's the get connected call
center. Real people ready to help you
enroll today. Or go online to
internetforallnow.org
to find a provider near you. You may
also qualify for a lowcost computer
through human IT. Connectivity is
[music] not a luxury in 2026. It's a
necessity and you deserve access just
like everybody else. Call 844-461-7893.
That's 844-461-7893.
KBLA's got you. If you missed any of
this, you can always go to our website
at kbla1580.com.
Brought to you by KBLA Talk 1580 in
partnership with the California Emerging
Technology Fund, CETF.
>> Smart.
unapologetic.
>> Apologetic.
>> You're riding [music] with Amanda Seals
on KBLA Talk 1580.
>> Yes. Yes. It's KBLA Talk 1580. I am
Amanda Seals here for the summer of
SEALs. Shout out to everybody joining
us, listening, tuning in. Uh we've been
talking about some things. If you're
just joining, we talked about Jay-Z
being a sellout. We talked about the
Democrats. uh supporting or sending
condolences to someone who is an
actually evil person. And um you know,
these are the types of things that that
I end up talking about. You know,
listen, I am the person
I am the person, y'all, who when you
invite me somewhere, just know that I'm
I'm I'm not I'm not gonna let I'm not
gonna let anything fly that is
discriminatory, that is denigrating,
etc. Like, I'm just not going to rock
with it. So, know that if you invite me
somewhere, I'm probably gonna bring up
Palestine. Like, when I went to Mark
Lamont Hill to Dr. Mark Hills wedding. I
was sitting next to this woman at the
like they seat you at like assigned
tables, assigned seating. And I turned
to her and I said, "Listen,
I'm not good at small talk. So, I need
you to please jump this off because if
somebody don't talk talk, if somebody
don't start talking soon, I'm gonna
start talking about Palestine."
Like, that's what it is. Nonetheless, we
all should be doing our due diligence to
build community, right? We know that
things are about to get very, very
topsyturvy. Anytime you see the
geopolitical analysts and the astrology
girlies on the same page, you should
know things is about to go haywire.
So, in that regard, our best efforts at
survival, at thriving are going to be in
community. So when my neighbor invited
me over the other day, I said, "Yeah, oh
my gosh, I'll come over." Because we had
gotten the opportunity to ride the train
together and you know, she she was
really cool. And so she invited me to
over because her mother and her auntie
and her sister were um over and then her
and her husband and they were drinking
some wine and she invited me to over. I
don't drink so she had me some salsa. So
I come through and while we're talking
her her mother who is um an Italian
woman, she was talking about well her
and her aunt who is Jamaican literally
wearing a shirt that says Wagwan.
They were talking about their travels
and they're like you know
septtogenarians and so they just be
getting into some Felman Louise type
antics. And so in the mix of this the
mother says yes. So we were robbed by
some gypsies. And I I just corrected her
calmly y'all. I need to calmly. I just
said Romani and she looked at me like
what am I talking about? So then she
says it again and she was like yeah so
you know the the gypsies you know they
were doing this and they were doing that
and I said Romani
and so I could see her brain processing
like why this lady over here keeps
saying Romani.
So they keep telling the story. The next
time that she mentions Romani she looks
at me in my eye and says I mean the next
time they mention Gypsy she looks at me
in my eye and says Gypsy. I said Romani.
And she was like, "Why do you keep
saying Romani?" I said, "Because gypsy
is a derogatory term." She was like,
"So, oh, come on. I mean, what's the big
deal?" I said, "The big deal is they
don't want to be called that." So then
we call them what they want to be
called, WHICH ROMANI. WELL, WE'VE ALWAYS
called them that. It's not a big deal.
It's no, it doesn't matter. It doesn't
matter. I said, "It does matter because
when a group of people say they don't
want to be called something, we respect
that." Well, that's what we've always
called them. That was It was not It
wasn't a problem before. And y'all,
I had to do it. I had to I had to hit
her with a hammer.
I had to bring
the N word with the eer out and I said,
"Well, we were once called
and now we are not because it is
unacceptable." And she said, "I would
never use that word." And I said,
"Exactly."
And then the the Jamaican grandmother
tried to clean it up like, "Okay, so how
do you spell Romani?" Nonetheless,
you know, I I encourage all of us to be
the truth translator in these spaces
because we can't let people get away
with the nonsense. We know better. We do
better. And when we come forward, we
going to keep on doing the same right
here at the Summer Seals.
>> It's a SEAL summer.
>> Amanda Seals,
[music]
>> only on KBLA Talk 1580.
This November, you'll decide [music] who
leads California. So, shouldn't you hear
directly from the people asking for your
vote? Join us for California Voices, a
political town hall and ballot [music]
forum Saturday, October 3rd, 2026. Meet
candidates running for governor,
lieutenant governor, attorney [music]
general, and other major statewide and
local offices, including mayor of Los
Angeles, [music] city attorney, and LA
County Sheriff. Get clear, nonpartisan
[music] breakdowns of the propositions
on your November ballot, both sides, no
spin, and ask your questions [music]
directly in real conversation, face to
face. California Voices is brought to
you by KBLA Talk 1580 [music] and the
Empowerment Congress, giving you the
information you need before you vote.
Mark your [music] calendar. Saturday,
October 3rd, 2026, California Voices.
Follow KBLA [music] 1580 for details and
download the KBLA 1580 app. Your vote,
your voice. Be there.
>> Turn it up and go tell somebody. Amanda
Seals is on the air. KBLA talk 1580.
>> Yeah.
All you had to do was pay us enough to
live. Said the man behind the can before
the flame was lit. Push come to shove.
Come from above to where the labor lives
down on the bottom. But the problems
where the board members sick executives
a ruling class that laughs in cast
system. I need to check them in [music]
the la. They never see the people coming
even when they us feel the power cuz
it's from within us. Indigenous are
talking by the moon before the dollar
was the idol. Before there was a Bible
before we [music] were trained to walk
single file and pledge allegiance to
politicians communal living. I hope
you're listening. I hope
>> Welcome, welcome, welcome, welcome,
welcome. It's your girl Amanda Seals
here at the summer of Seals KBLA Talk
1580. Thank y'all for joining me. I will
be here for yet another hour. We're so
happy to be back on radio and having a
space to talk about them bangs and also
just to remember just to just to be a
voice in the noise that centers critical
thinking. You know that thing critical
thinking that we have been consistently
convinced is irrelevant. Do you remember
that whole movement of who needs
college? Do you remember that? There was
like a whole movement in the last like
two years where I just saw started
seeing like this whole narrative of like
why go to college? College isn't for
anything. College is just going to give
you debt. What's the point of going to
college? And it was like yeah but all
these people in power they're not not
going to college. So you telling us not
to go to college but them people they
they still going to college. like that
that that that's the type of things
where your critical thinking
helps you sus out what the nonsense is,
what the scop is.
So, every show we will always do a
critical thinking exercise where I'm
going to present a concept to you and I
hope that you will take some time to
just ponder it, think about it, talk
about it amongst your friends, put it in
your group chat. I know we got old heads
on here that are still on the Facebook.
Put it on a Facebook. You know what I'm
saying? So, use the prompt to do your
own critical thinking exercise on the
Facebook. You feel me? So, let's get
into this week's critical thinking
exercise.
All right, critical thinking exercise
time. This week's critical thinking
exercise is in alignment with the
question I asked at this month's Radical
Rhythms Experience, which is a show that
I do every second Tuesday, sorry, every
second Wednesday of the month in Harlem,
New York at the Comedy and Harlem Comedy
Club where I use comedy and music and
commentary to bring us in to energy
work. And I know some of y'all are like,
"What is she talking about with this
energy work?" But even if you're saying
that, you're still listening. So you're
gonna hear about energy work. And one of
the things that we do with the show is
in the working on our energy, we put our
attention to something that is actually
useful and elevating to us because
remember where your attention goes, your
energy flows. So that la so the radical
women's experience that took place last
week. I asked what does freedom mean to
you?
Now let me throw some things out there
real quick. The concept of freedom is
not solely based in not being in slavery
or not being in prison. Freedom has many
levels. So as you're considering this, I
want you to think about freedom as it
relates to being able to be your
authentic self. Freedom as it relates to
being able to live in your passion,
freedom as it relates to being able to
move across borders and go where you
want to go, etc. So, what does freedom
mean to you? Is this week's critical
thinking exercise? Think about it.
Ponder it. When you see me on the
internet, I want you to answer because
I'm going to throw this up on the
internet on Instagram, Amanda Seals,
asking what does freedom mean to you?
And you can put your responses there and
if there's enough responses I will read
them here. So that is this week's
critical thinking exercise. What does
freedom mean to you? To me freedom means
options without limitations. When we
come forward we got more right here at
summer of seals.
>> KBLA 1580 Santa Monica.
>> I'm Amber Payton with BIN News. Now,
President Trump says he is declassifying
evidence he claims shows China
interfered in the 2020 election by
accessing millions of US voter files.
>> That information includes names,
addresses, phone numbers.
>> In a Thursday evening prime time
address, Trump accused the Biden
administration and others in government
of hiding the information. He says the
FBI is investigating a renewed calls for
Congress to pass his voter ID bill.
Black Maryland Governor Wes Moore says a
state task force has found rising scams,
fraud, and other barriers affecting
immigrant residents. The group will meet
with communities in the coming months to
identify concerns and improve access to
legal protections and resources.
And rapper Eminem's former wife, Kim
Scott, is facing charges after allegedly
attacking officers who responded to her
Michigan home following a reported
suicide attempt. TMZ says Scott tried to
bite one officer and kicked another
before being arrested. Get BIN news now
on demand 247 on the iHeart Radio app.
>> For victims of drunk and drug driving,
our grief is unique, but you are not
alone. You always have a place at MAD.
Call our 24-hour victim helpline at 877
MADH help or visit mAD.org.
>> This is the KBLA Sports Minute with Ray
Richardson.
>> I'M A BAD MAN.
>> The start of NFL training camps is just
around the corner. All 32 teams are
scheduled to begin preparations next
week for the 2026 season. First day of
camp for the Chargers [music] is July
23rd in Elsagundo. The Rams open camp on
July 25th at Lola Marry Mount. The first
day of the Rams camp could have some
drama. There's been a lot of chatter in
recent weeks that defensive lineman
Aaron Donald is giving serious thought
to coming out of retirement. The
35-year-old Donald retired in 2024.
Donald, a three-time defensive player of
the year, is the Rams all-time sacks
leader with 111. Stay tuned on that.
Tonight at 6, it's your Friday night
sports picks, out of bounds and prime
time. Join me and my co-host Neil Scar
Bro for 60 minutes of sports chatter
with some Blackbones flavor. You can
hang out with us on the KBLA YouTube
channel or hit us up at 1800-920-1580.
No debates, no speculation, just the
info you need. That's your KBLA Sports
Minute. I'm Ray Richardson on KBLA Talk
1580.
>> Let's do this.
>> We're heading into one of the most
important election seasons in a
generation. And with so much on the
line, your healthcare, your economy,
your neighborhood. You deserve more than
sound bites. You deserve the full story.
KBLA Talk 1580 is your trusted voice for
political coverage, commentary, and
[music] conversation. From local races
to national headlines, we bring you the
insight and perspective you need to make
sense of it all and make your voice
heard. Between now and November, a lot
will happen. A lot will change. But one
thing won't. KBLA Talk 1580 will be
right here keeping you informed, keeping
you engaged, and keeping it real. KBLA
Talk 1580, the place. The place for
politics.
We are here in the second hour of the
summer of Seals. It's your girl Amanda
Seals right here at KBLA Talk 1580. Make
sure you download the KBLA Talk 1580 app
so that you can listen to the show over
and over and over again and you also
support the work that is being done here
when you do so. So, shout out to Tavis
Smiley for bringing me in and putting me
on the airwaves again so I can speak my
truths. Let me also just say that when I
say speak my truths, like I'm not just
like speaking out my neck.
Like, my truths are grounded in facts.
All right, which I don't feel like can
be said for many folks. My truths are
found are grounded in in facts. And the
fact is we got a lot of noise out here,
a lot of chaos. See, I'm fine. A lot of
chaos is just swirling all the time.
It's like there's always something and
something and something and something
and it just keeps you disregulated.
And so I was asking folks on Instagram
this week to consider something. At what
point
do we say, "Okay, I can't just keep
taking a break every time there's too
much information because the information
isn't stopping."
So if I keep taking breaks, I literally
just keep being further and further from
the information and what I don't know
can't hurt me. So then what's the other
option? And I would suggest the other
option is learning how to process that
information. And what I mean by that is
that I feel that we have gotten into a
rhythm where we particularly folks on
social media, but I think y'all are even
doing this with your peoples, right?
where you see something that's
ridiculous, right? Like whether it's
like birthright citizenship being
contested or voting rights being rolled
back, you see that and you're like,
"What? That's crazy." And then you go
and you vent about it.
However, the venting rarely is
contextualized
as solutions. Um, the venting is rarely
bringing new information.
The venting oftentimes is literally just
that, a vent.
But here's the problem.
Every resistance movement that you know
of has come as a result of the people
being over it, of the people saying we
have had enough.
In order for it to get to that point,
pressure has to build.
So if you keep venting
by literal nature of the definition,
you're not allowing the pressure to
build.
The the pressure is constantly being
released.
And so you're never really processing
what's happening. You're literally just
it's coming in, it's coming out.
And now you do not have that pressure
buildup taking place to eventually lead
to actual resistance.
So that's where I feel like social media
has really gotten us in a way that a lot
of people don't talk about is that we
sit on there and we talk and we learn,
but we also are consistently venting.
And so we're losing that that pressure
build that forces us to say enough is
enough
because remember pressure pipes,
pressure also makes diamonds.
So, my challenge to you guys who are
listening, to y'all who are listening,
is the next time you see some nonsense,
right? Instead of just immediately doing
a comment, and by the way, this is not
easy because I've had to check myself on
this for the past couple days because I
was like, "Oh, girl, you're not you not
even successful at your own challenge."
So, I had to step it up. So my challenge
to y'all is that when you see something
that is negative that is just it
triggers something in you, right? It
makes you compelled to respond. Don't
don't respond because at this point when
we respond it's a release and it feels
to our physical body like we've done
something. Even if our mind knows we
didn't, our body feels that and thus our
body is not responding to the actual
thing that is threatening us.
And we have to have our minds and our
bodies connected and we are currently
disconnected.
So my challenge to you is instead of
immediately responding and giving your
body that release, that somatic release,
pil,
hold it in your mind
and consider it.
Consider its source. Consider the
repercussions of it. Consider even how
me however off-the-wall you want to
think it is you you think the idea is
consider
well how could this be addressed
no matter how criminal you you think it
is consider
how could this be addressed how could
this be undermined how could this be
disempowered etc
right
also what this does is it is reigniting
igning your imagination
and we don't really got no imagination
no more because everything is being
shown to us all the goddamn time. We're
over stimulated.
So we have to basically give oursel like
exercises to reinvigorate
these capabilities. You know there was a
time where humans had other senses. We
didn't just have five senses. You know
right now it looks like okay we got
taste we got touch we got hearing we got
feeling we got smell we also had other
senses and it's shown by the artifacts
that they find it's shown by the
pyramids etc we had a six sense
I would
s I I suggest that there's a possibility
that we are now in a time where we are
seeing ourselves lose another sense
like we're literally literally losing
our ability to feel
like our empathy and I don't mean like
physically feel with your fingers but I
mean like feel with your body like your
empathy like we're losing that
so that is making us less and less human
and then we got AI and they like we
about to put this thing in here anyway
so we don't need the humans.
So that's my challenge, folks. This
week, when you see something that's some
nonsense, instead of immediately
responding with your two cents, with
your frustration, with your quippy,
witty reply,
you know, instead of getting in those
comments and arguing with strangers who
are sitting at their desk just like
you're sitting at your desk, who have
some ridiculous avatar that's like a
duck smoking a cigar
while driving a Honda, you know? Don't
argue. Don't let yourself get sucked
into the negative energy pull. Instead,
take back your energy.
Reinvigorate your imagination and
consider
what could be the fix. When we come
forward, we're going to talk about Nolan
Wells. Rest in peace to the young
brother. This is the summer of seals.
>> Keeping it real,
>> keeping it raw,
>> keeping it rooted. [music] More of
Amanda Seals
>> when we come forward
>> on KBLA Talk 1580. 1880.
[music]
>> Are you drowning in IRS tax debt? Angela
was. She called Civic Tax Relief and
saved over $80,000. Felicia was having
health problems. Got behind on her
taxes, interest, and penalties were
adding up. She called Civic Tax Relief
and saved over $15,000. [music]
Civic Tax Relief is a professional tax
negotiation firm that can protect you
from the IRS. If you're getting
collection letters, call [singing] Civic
Tax Relief for a free consultation. They
will go to work helping you discover all
the relief programs you may qualify for
for free. James owed the IRS $37,000.
Civic Tax Relief represented him against
the IRS. And by the time everything was
completed, he did not owe the IRS
anything. If you are in trouble with the
IRS, call [music] Civic Tax Relief for
your free consultation now. 8002002257.
[music]
8002002257.
Get a free consultation and real tax
relief. Call 8002002257. [music]
8002002257.
>> Ready to order?
>> Yes. We're earning unlimited 3% cash
back on dining and entertainment with a
Capital 1 Saver card. So, let's just get
one of everything.
>> Everything.
>> Fire everything. The Capital 1 Saver
Card is at table 27 and they're earning
unlimited 3% cash back. Yes, chef.
>> This is so nice.
>> Had a feeling you'd want 3% cash back on
dessert.
>> Ooh, Terramisu.
>> Earn unlimited 3% cash back on dining
and entertainment with the Capital 1
Saver Card. Capital 1. What's in your
wallet?
>> Terms apply. See capital 1.com for
details.
>> KBLA Talk 1580. We've got a lot to talk
about.
>> KBLA Talk 1580 connecting you with
services and [music] solutions. These
are hard times for housing in America.
Too many in our community face [music]
barriers to safe housing, behavioral
health care, and affirming spaces for
healing, particularly [music]
those impacted by poverty and stigma or
incarceration. Rooted in South LA, AMAD
supports impacted communities through
housing, wellness, and leadership
development. Ahmad provides culturally
responsive, peer-led support from
transitional housing, and mental health
services to leadership development and
youth empowerment. They offer safe,
affirming houses for youth, transgender
women, and formerly incarcerated
individuals. [music] Therapy and peer
support with a focus on healing trauma
in black communities, HIV prevention and
care, free testing, education, and
wraparound services for whole person
wellness. Standing in the gap with
health, [music] housing, and hope. Reach
out to Ahmad Institute at 323-569-1610.
That's 323-5691610.
[music]
or visit a m a.org.
This is a community call to action from
KBLA Talk 1580.
>> Your daily dose of real. Let's get back
to more of Amanda Seals on KBLA [music]
Talk 1580.
Hey everybody,
it is Amanda Seals here and we are in
our second hour at the Summer of Seals.
It's time for us to get into another
Black News story.
So thankfully many of us have been
talking adnauseium loudly and not simply
letting the case of Nolan Wells, the
young man in Mississippi, go under the
rug. Nolan Wells, uh, high schooler,
young brother, went on a boat ride with,
uh, some white friends and never made it
home. What we now know is that
the original story, which is that he was
left on this like island that they have
out there, like a little archipelago of
islands, that he was left there by his
boys and that he didn't come back. um
and they don't know what happened to
him. Now, anybody who has seen even half
of an episode of First 48 knew off rip,
no, that ain't true. None of that. And
anybody who has been black in America
with a consciousness of being black in
America knows that if a black child
leaves home
with all white classmates and doesn't
come home, the odds are very high,
almost
unquestionably high, that their fate was
determined by those white classmates.
And why can we say that confidently,
right? Like some people I saw saying
like, "You guys are jumping to
conclusions." And I was like, "Please
shut up. Shut it up."
Because it is the awareness that that is
even a possibility
that has actually kept so many folks
alive, right? Like it's the
consciousness that
these folks in numbers,
especially when they have privilege,
have been known to cause harm. And you
know, it's that it's the same thing like
when Dr. Dr. Muhammad Ali when Muhammad
Ali was being interviewed and they asked
him, "Well, why can't you just say every
white person is racist?" And he was
like, "Man, if a bunch of snakes came in
here, you think I'm thinking about which
snake is poisonous. No, I'm getting all
I'm getting rid of all the snakes. I'm
not going to try and figure it out. I'm
just going to make sure that I'm not
getting around none of them snakes." And
that is a survival instinct that so many
of us here in the United States have had
to learn the hard way. that in those
type of situations, it doesn't mean that
you got to consider everybody uh it's
not doesn't mean that you have to look
at everybody indicting them as as foul,
but it means that you have to have your
consciousness perked up, right? So, it
was no surprise when many of us learned
that Nolan
actually did come back on that boat.
For the record, it came back on a boat
alive.
And the thing about
the thing about the truth is that it has
a way of coming to the surface.
They first of all tried to say that this
young baby, this 17-year-old athlete fit
that he died drowning.
Instead, what was revealed
was a photo of Nolan that same evening
in a swimming pool
with these same friends
with shots lined up on the side of the
pool.
Now,
this is when things started getting very
obviously clear that this is all a miss.
And you know, Ben Crump, shout out to
Ben Crump for stepping in and saying,
"Okay, now we gonna get we gonna get
this going because what they discovered
was
Nolan's phone had been taken by the boys
and scrubbed. His Snapchat had been
deleted. Like texts had been deleted."
However, what they failed to remember
was that in certain cases, if you have
it set up a certain way, if you post
something on your Instagram,
it's going to post to your Threads
account.
They did not take account for that. And
so, the photo with the time stamp was
still available on the Threads account.
Now, these children did not tell Nolan's
parents that they had his phone until
two days later. Even though the parents
had been looking for the phone when they
was looking for Nolan, they had the
phone the whole goddamn time. And one of
these kids, their mother is a judge. To
my understanding, the mother who's the
judge is the owner of the house where
this party took place.
And so now that that gets revealed,
folks start to talking. I mean, there's
so many people in this pool that there's
got to be witnesses. And sure enough,
one of the people, one of the young
ladies in the pool starts posting on in
on uh Twitter on the Twitter and says
that Nolan got jumped at the party. Now
again, this is all alleged. I'm just re
I'm just repeating what was written that
Nolan got jumped in the part at the
party and that he was not allowed to go
home. He was coughing up blood and that
his his cranium was caved in.
Then his body was dumped
on that island.
So,
the medical examiner
who is assigned to this case
has been revealed to be attached to two
other cases
where there's a mysterious death
surrounding a black child that she was
an impediment to solving.
Let's talk about the case of Shannon
Wilson, 13year-old. I think you all
might remember this. Friends drowned him
in a creek in Mississippi.
Said they didn't know what happened
though.
And the autopsy
was not performed because she said they
don't do autopsies for drowning.
What?
So then the family had to pay to get an
independent autopsy done.
The woman's name is Stacy Turner. I want
to shout out the white lady. She's a
lawyer. Kimria Lee. Kimber Lee who put
this out. That's my kind of whiting.
Okay. That's my kind of whiting. You not
you're not in allyship. You in
co-conspirator behaviors when you start
doing this. When you start calling out
these people in these public positions
and positioning them publicly in their
heinous discriminatory actions. Yeah.
Let let's never forget that Ahmad Aubrey
in Georgia that was swept under the rug
by the DA. The only reason that we knew
that we became aware of the fact that
Ahmad Aubrey was lynched by by gunfire
by these thugs driving in trucks behind
him while he's running for his life. The
only reason we know about that is
because someone who was in that office
snitched. Their conscience got the best
of them. That's the only reason we know
about that.
In this case, this white lady said,
"I'mma do some research." And I'm I
appreciate her doing that because it
brings also to light just the the level
of systemic oppression that we're
talking about. This what we This is what
we mean when we say systemic racism.
This is what we're talking about.
Let me calm down.
Systemic racism is the capability for
white people in power
to use their positions of power to
impede
life, liberty, and the pursuit of
happiness for black people, for anybody.
Actually,
this young man's death
was absolutely
foul
and everybody who is involved
should be held accountable on multiple
levels. And the only way that's going to
happen is if we keep on amplifying it.
Do y'all remember Tamila Hosford?
Tam Hosford was a sister in Atlanta. I
think it is in Atlanta.
Went to a sleepover with some white
ladies in Atlanta. It's not like she
left the country. She went to a
sleepover with some white ladies.
There's a picture of them on the
sectional and they're in their jammies.
Next morning she was found on the front
lawn,
deceased.
And then them women ain't never paid no
price for that. It all just that's it.
They said we don't know what happened.
Now let Becky have been out there after
spending the night with Nuana, Tasha,
Shakira, and Tahira.
I'm stating the obvious, but sometimes
the obvious got to be stated just to
remind us.
This young man, Nolan Wells, his body
was found and it had to be identified by
dental records.
That is that is the harm that was done
to him.
I had to be identified by dental
records.
And now man, at the time of me
recording,
his mama, her face has been used to make
an AI video.
What? An AI video saying that she's not
going to have a service for her son. And
she had to come out and say like, "No,
this is not I never said that. So,
they're using the deep fake and now the
prosecution or I the DA I guess is
saying like, well, this is this is um
impeding the case, etc.
Of course, it is right.
Listen, this is the land of no justice.
And
and I I know that this is not new, but
it's loud. And I wanna I want to tell
y'all another brother lost his life that
same day on the 250th anniversary of the
United States
in another mysterious fashion.
I can't I can't say that that is
that's not that that's auspicious
in the in the in the most terrible of
ways.
And of course, this is all in
Mississippi.
Let's talk about July 4th for a second,
though. Are y'all still celebrating July
4th?
And I know y'all gonna say something
like, "Well, it's just a good time for
us to get together with family." Okay,
but like under what terms? Are y'all
getting together with family and wearing
American flag trunks?
Are y'all getting together with family
and and having like full celebration
time without even taking a moment to
acknowledge the absolute hypocrisy
of July 4th?
How how
I've never understood that to keep it a
buck. I black people I get it. We
celebrate July 4th just in the sense
that like we should get every day off.
I respect it. I respect it. We should we
should get every day off and tenfold.
However, again where energy goes where
sorry however where our attention goes
our energy flows.
We have got to be far more conscious of
where we are sending our energy. The
same way we have to be far more
conscious of where we are sending our
children.
I remember when I was in middle school
and I wanted to go to a party. these two
white kids, Amy and Eric, were having,
they were twins, and they had a DJ. And
I don't know if y'all understand, but as
an ex as an excial, a DJ was a very big
deal in the 90s. When somebody was
having a DJ at their party in middle
school, that was like, oh, they got
money.
So, I tell my mom, I want to go to this
party. And her first question is, will
there be black children there? There's
going to be other black kids there. And
I'm just like, I mean, I don't know. I
think Kenny Lane will be there.
So, she said, "Okay, you go." So, I get
to the party, y'all. 12. I'm in my Sam
and Libbyy's. And I'm there with Kenny
Lane. He's there. I'm not like with him,
but both of us are there. You know, the
polka dots in the party.
And
the DJ starts playing Slam. Now, for
those of y'all who remember Slam Onyx,
when Slam would come on, it was a time,
and this was also a time where the white
kids were feeling very confident about
their hip-hop skills. Okay, this is
when, you know, criminal um what was
that movie? Criminal,
no, Dangerous Mind, Dangerous Minds had
come out. And so, the white kids were
feeling very confident because they had
learned the words to Kulio's verse,
Tulio's raps. And so, when when Onyx
Slam came on, they was in it. They was
having a blast. Slam.
And what the lyrics go,
let the boys be boys.
And I realized
that what they were singing was slam
white power, white power, let the boys
be white.
And then everything started to go in
slow motion.
I was I was like, "Wait, is is what's
happening happening?" And like every
black person in a racist scenario, I
immediately started looking for the
other black person so that we could have
a vibranium mind meld
to confirm, is this racist? Yes, this is
racist.
Slam. White power. White power. Let the
boys be white. I said, "Oh man, I gotta
get out of here. I gotta get out of
here." I look over for Kenny.
Clinty over there singing SLAM WIPE OUT.
MAN, I'M ALONE. I'm alone.
I had to weave my way through these
future clansmen
to go to call my mama in the kitchen on
the phone on the wall with long cord. I
called my mom.
She answered the phone. What's
happening? What's going on?
I need you to come pick me up.
Oh, really?
What happened?
Racism.
She said, "My I didn't even take my
shoes off. I'm coming now." She came and
picked me up.
She came pick me up.
These are real scenarios. And it's not
that I didn't have black friends. It's
not that Nolan didn't have black
friends, but sometimes some of us, we're
we're in the mix of a bunch of different
folks, right? Like we we not eating
lunch with just one group. We moving
through the through the through the
through the movements
because our our our energy is here for
everybody.
And unfortunately, Nolan met a tragic
fate
by his energy
being stolen by these energy vampires
who continue
to torture us here in this United
States. And we are not going to let it
continue. Rest in peace to Nolan. We are
going to keep lifting you up. When we
come forward, we got more show for you.
Keep it locked.
>> Broadening your moral imagination. This
is Amanda Seals on KBLA Talk 1580.
>> Don't sweat the technique.
>> I'm Amber Payton with BIN News. Now, WBA
boxing champion Javvante Tank Davis is
facing criminal and civil trials over an
alleged domestic violence incident
involving his former girlfriend.
>> Any offer, any uh counter offer you'll
consider?
>> At at this moment, just follow what we
got. He is charged with battery, false
imprisonment, and attempted kidnapping.
A status hearing is set for September
15th with a possible trial in the coming
months.
President Trump is blaming Canada for
wildfire smoke affecting the Midwest and
Northeast. Trump says poor forest
management is fueling the problem and
plans to call Canadian Prime Minister
Mark Carney about it. And LeBron James
says he is close to announcing his next
team after deciding to leave the Lakers.
Possible destinations include Cleveland,
Miami, Philadelphia, Minnesota, and
Golden State. James previously won
championships with both the Cavaliers
and Heat. Get BIN news now on demand 247
on the iHeart Radio app.
Think it Up is an initiative to activate
studentpowered teacher-led learning
projects. Students and teachers, how can
you spark great learning experiences in
your classrooms today? Join at
thinkup.org.
Is this potato?
>> This is the KBLA Sports Minute with Ray
Richardson.
>> I'm a bad man.
>> The start of NFL training camps is just
around the corner. All 32 teams are
scheduled to begin preparations next
week for the 2026 season. First day of
camp [music] for the Chargers is July
23rd in Elsagundo. The Rams open camp on
July 25th at Lola Marry Mount. The first
day of the Rams camp could have some
drama. There's been a lot of chatter in
recent weeks that defensive lineman
Aaron Donald is giving serious thought
to coming out of retirement. The
35-year-old Donald retired in 2024.
Donald, a three-time defensive player of
the year, is the Rams all-time sacks
leader with 111. Stay tuned on that.
Tonight [music] at 6, it's your Friday
night sports pick. Out of bounds and
prime time. Join me and my co-host Neil
Scarro for 60 minutes of sports chatter
with some Blackbones flavor. You can
hang out with us on the KBLA YouTube
channel or hit us up at 1800-920-1580.
No debates, no speculation, just the
info you need. That's your KBLA Sports
Minute. I'm Ray Richardson on KBLA Talk
1580.
Let's do this.
>> We're heading into one of the most
important election seasons in a
generation. And with so much on the
line, your healthcare, your economy,
your neighborhood, you deserve more than
sound bites. You deserve the full story.
KBLA Talk 1580 is your trusted voice for
political [music] coverage, commentary,
and conversation. From local races to
national headlines, we bring you the
insight and perspective you need to make
sense of it all and make your voice
heard. Between now and November, a lot
will happen. A lot will change. But one
thing won't. KBLA Talk 1580 will be
right here keeping you informed, keeping
you engaged, and keeping it real. KBLA
Talk 1580. The place for politics.
>> Let's do this.
>> Los Angeles is listening and finally Los
Angeles is being heard. This is KBLA
Talk 1580.
Let me put my hard hat on, go back
outside, and see if these
procrastination crunch construction
crews have shown up yet. I'm saving
space for grace. But if these trucks
don't show up soon, well, you already
know.
>> Destination Princaw,
your time is up.
With a KBLA Talk 1580 editorial, I'm
Tavis Smiley. KBLA Talk 1580 and
Bethesda Temple Church invite residents,
churches, businesses, and community
leaders along the Prince corridor to
join a vitally important community
conversation. Thursday, July 30th, 6:30
p.m. at Bethesda Temple Church, 4909
Crrenshaw Boulevard. [music]
For years now, this community has been
living with unkempt promises and the
devastating effects of the unfinished
destination Crrenshaw construction
[music]
project, leaving residents, businesses,
and churches to deal with myriad
problems, including the loss of [music]
parking, restricted access, traffic
congestion, and a lack of emergency
vehicle access when it matters most. For
years now, Procrastination Crrenshaw has
directly contributed [music]
to the loss of customer revenue for
local blackowned businesses and sadly
has forced the closure of some
businesses along this 1.3 mile corridor.
[music] For years now, churches have
been experiencing decreased attendance
due to the elimination of parking and
social [music] service programs for
vulnerable fellow citizens have been
altogether halted. [music]
For years now, residents have watched
their quality of life erode, and nothing
has been done about it. If they think
they can get away with treating black
folk like secondass citizens, they
better think again.
>> You better think about what you're
trying to do to me. This town hall
meeting is a reckoning, a public
witness, [music]
an opportunity for impacted community
members to share their experiences
[music]
for the public record as we prepare to
hold those responsible [music]
accountable for this enduring nightmare.
So, please join us Thursday, July 30th,
[music] 6:30 p.m. at Bethesda Temple
Church, 4909 Krenshaw Boulevard.
>> [music]
>> This town hall meeting is free and open
to the public, but registration is
required [music] at kbl1580.com.
With a KBLA Talk 1580 editorial, I'm
Tavis Smiley, and as always, we welcome
[music] your feedback.
>> Oh, no she didn't.
>> It's a scorching sill summer.
>> Oh, yes, she did.
>> On KBLA Talk 1580.
It is the summer of seals here at KBLA
Talk 1580. I am Amanda Seals back at it
on these radio waves. If you did not
know about my Patreon, Patreon is a
subscription community where you are
able to support artists uh directly,
right? So, it's not necessarily like
buying, you know, merch or buying an
album, etc., etc., but it is actually
supporting their work while supporting
yourself. For instance, my Patreon
community, the Seal Squad, is a
community of folks that support each
other through information. Sometimes
we've supported each other financially.
Uh we're going to be supporting each
other on a trip that's going to Grenada.
And every week we meet on Wednesdays and
you know just change it from like this
like weird social media parasocial
interaction to a real one where we are
sharing knowledge and sharing jokes etc
etc. Um if I say etc etc one more time I
am really gonna be upset myself. So
anywh who supporting artists is
important and supporting yourself is
important. So if you can do the th the
two at the same damn time well why not
right? So go to patreon.com
that's po
n.comamanda
[music]
seals and you can join my Patreon and
you can be in the mix and you know you
can also sign up for my newsletter. I
got a lot of things. I got a lot of
things. I got a store, Amanda Exports.
You know, this is what happens when you
divest from celebrity. You realize like,
okay, I can't just rely before I was
relying on the possibility of getting
bookings, etc., etc. Nope, nope, nope.
Now I got to do it myself. I got to
handle my business myself because that's
where we are, you You know, and there's
something beautiful to seeing your own
creations and to seeing them grow and
expand, you know, naturally and
organically and knowing that they came
from an honest source, from a true
source, which brings me
which brings me to this story that I did
not know about.
So, did you know that there is an entire
court case that's been going on for a
couple years now? And it's it's really
hasn't gone further because like the
record labels are being able to suppress
it, but it exists.
There is a court case that is trying to
sue
many of the big names in Regaton. So
we're talking like you know Daddy Yankee
and Luis Fony and Boni.
The grounds for the case
are that this song Fish Market by group
Steelely and Cle
which dropped in 1989
is the drum sample
that is used throughout all of Reaton.
That was the original sample and it has
been used as the
basis of regaton
and they're saying you owe us
and reaton artists maybe not reaton
artists but definitely the labels are
saying no we don't well what do you all
think because listen
you can't say that reaton did not come
from reggae Okay. Reggae is literally in
the word reaton.
For those who may not be familiar with
reaton, reaton is like Latin dance
reggae. I think that's like a fair
discrimination.
I mean, sorry, a fair description.
Um, and we know that hip-hop artists get
hit in the head all the time for
sampling,
right? Like that's a big thing. So, how
the hell y'all formed an entire genre of
music off of this one song and you don't
think that you got to compensate those
people, particularly when y'all are
caked up? Regaton is like an entire
global phenomena. How would you not be
responsible for paying cle and stevie? I
mean steely and cle
craziness. But that's that theft. You
know what I'm saying? That's the
international property theft that we
see. I mean that's sorry that's
intellectual property theft that we see
all the time. And I
I have never been a Daton fan. And now I
feel like I have a like a justifiable
reason for why because people are always
like what do you mean? Why you don't
know who
and now I can be like because
stealing from reggae
okay and don't like them don't like that
don't like it
but you see I always say that the
Caribbean is the Africa of the west
because our resources in the Caribbean
are constantly being taken and usurped
and we get looked at like I mean why
y'all upset about this like it's ours
now. NAFTA completely undermined the
North the North American free trade
agreement completely undermined like
Caribbean trade sovereignty because it
made it so that essentially the US and
Canada get to deter determine the prices
of everything that's being traded
between them and the Caribbean countries
though we do be sending though we do
though we do be celebrating independence
Today we're not independent.
We still have the queen on our money in
many cases.
Yeah. So it's not like we are truly
sovereign nations. And so that's why
when NAFTA took place, like they
basically just said, "Well, this is what
we're doing now and you got to do it
because it's what we own."
And so here we go with Regaton. Mind
you, Puerto Rican artists are of course
a very big part of Regaton and Puerto
Rico is a colony. So you would think
that they would have a certain
sensitivity
to the colonizing because they are being
colonized and they're actually acting
like colonizers in this context. And so
that was a very surprising story for me.
What I also didn't like though was that
it was covered by I think Billboard or
Rolling Stone and they were saying that
it's just like a nonsensical case. Like
this is just hogwash. This is
preposterous.
It seems to always be preposterous
whenever black folks are like, "Hey,
so you know that thing you stole from
us, we should actually get that back or
at the very least be compensated for it
since you keep like coming up off of it
that ends up being presented as this
like nonsensical
whimsical concept
when
theft
by the colonizer. It just seems, you
know, it's just it's very casually
accepted. Let's not forget the country
music was stolen from black folks in the
US. You know, when you look at the AMAs,
like I mean, sorry, the CAS,
it's a bunch of white neo babies.
They're doing country music now. But
country music came from black folks.
Okay? That's where country music came
from. Rock and roll came from black
folks. It didn't come from Death
Leopard.
It didn't come from that. It came from
black folks. Rosetta Thor
Richard, etc.
We are no stranger to our musical forms
being co-opted. Don't get me started on
Elvis, etc. We know about the white
labels,
right? We know about literally white
people covering black music.
We know about the R&B chart and the
segregation of music, right? Because
they would put black records only on the
R&B charts. They weren't allowed to be
on the pop charts even though they were
hit tunes. Like let's look about
Mottown. We know that.
But I'd never heard it outside of the
US.
So this was news to me, y'all.
This was news to me. And um as somebody
who inhabits both the Caribbean and the
US in my body, I am now on a complete
regaton boycott. Not that I ever liked
it, but now it's official tissue.
There'll be no winding up. I mean, even
when I listen to Bad Bunny, I skip all
the records that are records. At this
point, I'm basically skipping Bad Bunny
in general because he kissed a Zionist
on TV, aka Lady Gaga, at the Super Bowl,
which grossed me out.
Totally. So, yeah, they jacked it.
Full-time jack move. And I hope that
they don't give up this case. I hope
they continue going because at the end
of the day, now I know about it. And so,
it's literally getting it's going to get
more steam by the having more visibility
and the visibility is growing. So, shout
out to Clevy and Steelely for making
that beat back in 1989. Get your paper.
When we come forward, I'mma tell you how
black I feel today.
>> The conversation you didn't know you
were waiting for. Amanda Seals. Only on
KBLA Talk 1580. 1580. 1580. 1580.
>> Listen up KBLA delegation. We have
something you need to hear right now.
You may qualify for lowcost home
internet. And we're not talking about a
catch. This is real. Many internet
service providers offer lowcost internet
plans if anyone in your household is
enrolled in CalFresh, medical, SSI, or
is income eligible. There are a lot of
families in our community who deserve to
be connected. Here's all you do. [music]
Call 844-461-7893.
That's the get connected call center.
Real people ready to help you enroll
today or go online to
internetforallnow.org
to find a provider near you. You may
also qualify for a lowcost computer
through human IT. Connectivity is not a
luxury in 2026. It's a necessity and you
deserve access just like everybody else.
Call 8444-461-7893.
That's 844-461-7893.
KBLA's got you. If you missed any of
this, you can always go to our website
at kbla1580.com.
Brought to you by KBLA Talk 1580 in
partnership with the California Emerging
Technology Fund, CF.
>> Number 14.
That's where Talkers Magazine ranked
Tabis Smiley on their heavy hundred list
of the 100 most important talk radio
hosts in America. Join Tabis weekdays
[music] 9:00 a.m. to noon or 9:00 p.m.
to midnight only on KBLA
158.
[screaming]
>> Real talk, no filter. Amanda Seals on
KBLA Talk 1580.
I really feel so
about it.
Y'all want me to sing my song?
They get punched in the face.
Everybody thinks they're a man.
Tell they got to run their own race.
Well,
you can march to your own drum.
But can you handle freedom?
Can you imagine?
>> Yes. Yes, y'all. It is your girl Amanda
Seals here at the Summer of Seals. Hope
you liked that track. It is uh a sample
of a a portion of my song Stardust Remix
off my album Truth Translator. I just
dropped Truth Translator album and you
can check it out at amanda Diva. That's
my music name. Amanda Diva.bandamp.com.
One day I'll tell y'all the history
behind Amanda Diva name for those of
y'all who don't know about it. But in
the meantime, in between time, it's time
for us to find out how black do I feel
today?
>> [crying]
>> Let me tell you how black I feel today.
I feel not too much on black folks.
Black. All right. Now, I talked about
this on the Instagrams. I'm gonna talk
about it right here, just in case you
missed it.
I've been seeing a lot of content
creators
making it their business to critique
black folks, particularly those who are
not in political positions. So, I'm not
really tripping too much off the ones
who are in political positions, but like
critiquing celebrities and sports
people, etc., etc.,
um about their in their their
inactivism, etc. And my thing is, leave
that to us.
Leave that to the black folks. There's
not even enough time honestly in white
folks day to talk about anybody other
than white folks. I mean [laughter]
because the list baby actually we got a
list they got an archive
of folks past present who need to be
addressed. Let's just start with the
Epste files. So it's like honestly my
mindboggling to me like why why why do
you feel comfortable now
like really going off on black folks and
I think at the end of the day it always
ends up because it's clicks right you do
a video about Beyonce or Jay-Z or Cat
Williams or any or Oprah you're going to
get clicks this is the dangerous part
though even if your criticism is legit
okay for instance I saw a video where
this white girl was going off because of
a reference Cat Williams made to the
Gaza Strip being blown to rubble when he
was on that football player's um podcast
back in April 2024.
And he had made this reference saying
like if someone something to like
something to the effect of like if
someone accuses him of lying or
something like that like he's gonna he's
gonna Gaza strip it, he's going to bring
it to rebel, etc.
I gotta stop saying etc. It's killing
me. Sorry, I'm coming back to radio,
y'all. Just let me let me just ease back
in. I'mma get right. I'mma get right.
So, this video is this girl going off
saying he it's it's about children. It's
about It's like, okay, cut it out.
You're you're this is faux rage. And I'm
not saying that it's faux rage in that
you are not that upset about children
being harmed in. But we are leaving out
of context that this video happened in
January of 2024 and that to be quite
honest due to the SIA the knowledge,
awareness and full understanding of the
truth behind what has been taking place
in Philistine for the last century has
been very very quieted. And many black
folks absolutely did not know the truth.
If you were watching mainstream media,
they was lying to you every day, telling
you that it was something that it
wasn't. So, it wouldn't be surprising to
me that Cat Williams would consider, you
know, the the framework of what's going
on in an incorrect way. So, to come now
in 2026 and act like you are so mad
about it is like that's nuts. Leave it
to black folks. Black folks are going to
take care of black folks. We will call
out the black folks because whenever
y'all start calling out black folks, you
have your predominantly non-black
audience sitting there talking about a
black person and it's going to
eventually get racist. So, how black do
I feel today? Not too much on black
folks. When we come forward, we're going
to close it out with a public sales
announcement. Keep it luck, y'all.
>> Come on, you can admit it. She [music]
says what you're thinking. You're locked
in with Amanda Seals.
>> Only on KBLA Talk 1580.
>> You go, girl.
Hi, this is Chris Holden, former mayor
of Pasadena, former California [music]
Assembly Member and CEO of LA Fire
Justice.
>> Join Chris Holden and LA Fire Justice
for the 27th annual community block
party and resource fair Saturday,
[music] August 1st from 3:00 to 7:00
p.m. on the 500 block of East Jackson
Street in Pasadena. Bring [music] the
whole family for an afternoon of live
entertainment, games, activities, arts,
and crafts, and a special performance by
Altadena's own Grammy nominated R&B
artist, John B. Hosted [music] by James
Far of KDLA talk 1580s conversation live
Altadena Rising. Eaten fire survivors
can connect with local organizations,
recovery partners, and speak with the LA
Fire Justice team about [music] your
rights, their case against Edison, and
how you can join them in the fight to
hold them accountable and seek the
compensation you deserve. Come be part
of an afternoon of community connection
and support. LA Fire Justice is proud to
sponsor Conversation Live Altadena
Rising with James Far on KBLA Talk 1580.
Advertising Douglas Fox law of Douglas
[music] Fox 221 street Pasadena
California 91101 with the attorney
responsible for the profit of this
advert chrisen.org
this November [music]
you'll decide who leads California. So
shouldn't you hear directly [music] from
the people asking for your vote? Join us
for California Voices a political town
hall and ballot forum [music] Saturday
October 3rd 2026. Meet candidates
running for governor, lieutenant
governor, [music] attorney general, and
other major statewide and local offices,
including mayor of Los Angeles, city
attorney, [music] and LA County Sheriff.
Get clear, nonpartisan breakdowns of the
propositions on your November ballot,
[music] both sides, no spin, and ask
your questions directly in real
conversation, face to face. California
Voices is brought to you by [music] KBLA
Talk 1580 and the Empowerment Congress,
giving you the information you need
before you vote. Mark [music] your
calendar. Saturday, October 3rd, 2026,
California Voices. Follow KBLA 1580 for
details and [music] download the KBLA
1580 app. Your vote, your voice. Be
there.
>> Culture, politics, truth.
>> It's a seal summer. with Amanda Seals on
KBLA Talk 1580.
>> Welcome back.
It's your girl Amanda Seals here
wrapping up the first episode of the
Summer of Seals here at KBLA Talk 1580.
Remember to download the app so that you
can check me out every Friday 12 to 2:00
p.m. Pacific and 4 to 6 PM Pacific.
Let's get into how we will close the
show every week. A public seals
announcement.
PSA
>> public seals announcement.
>> So
being here back on radio is something
I'm really happy about.
I really take my gift of being able to
share information, to inspire people, to
ignite people very, very seriously. And
for those who've been watching my
journey over the past really like the
past three years, you've seen a person
really shift and the the shifting was
shifting out from behind like masks that
I had created to kind of fit in and to
get in the mix of things and not feel
like an alien. as well as just you know
kind of the ways in which we contort
ourselves to go along with society even
though we don't even think that society
is the thing to go along with. The other
the biggest thing though is what I want
to sh what I want to say in this PSA is
that the reason I'm able to be here
doing this radio show is because I'm
still here.
You know, sometimes you don't even know
where you're going when you get up and
try again, but you still just need to
get up and keep going. And that is for a
lot of folks who are listening, that is
faith. Um, however, for a lot of folks,
we we we we are tricked into thinking if
we don't have like a specific plan, if
we don't know the goal yet, if we don't
have a clear purpose, then we're
useless.
And I'm going to be the first to tell
you that as somebody who had the wind
completely knocked out of her, who had a
whole smear campaign against her by
black media, then a whole smear campaign
against her by Zionists, then a whole by
Jewish Zionist, by then a whole game uh
put against her by black Democrats, I
can tell you that the reason I am still
here
is not just because I care, because I
do, but also because I just refuse
refused to give up.
I just refused. I just refused to go
quietly. And people ask me all the time,
Amanda, how do you keep this energy? How
do you stay focused?
And what I what I tell them is that
there really is no other option.
There's just no other option. Like, this
is what it is. We're here. I'm here. And
the energy that I give to you all, as
long as it's here, I'm going to keep
giving it. And when they ask me, "But
where does that energy come from?" I I
wish I I really don't know the answer. I
maybe it's my ancestors. Maybe it's
future me energizing me. Perhaps it's my
connectivity to the earth. As we know,
it is a battery.
Nonetheless, my message today is don't
when they when they knock you down,
which life inevitably does,
always remember
that what happens to you
is for you.
Choose your path.
Choose how the ways in which people
shift and harm and project upon you.
Choose the ways in which you use that to
elevate, to be inspired, and to continue
to keep going. It's been a great one,
y'all. Summer of Seals. I'll be right
back at you next week. Thank you for
joining. I'm Amanda Seals.
>> KBLA 1580 Santa Monica.
>> I'm Amber Payton with BIN News. Now, WBA
boxing champion Javvante Tank Davis is
facing criminal and civil trials over an
alleged domestic violence incident
involving his former girlfriend.
>> Any offer, any uh counter offer you'll
consider
>> at this moment. Just follow the guard.
Okay.
>> He is charged with battery, false
imprisonment, and attempted kidnapping.
A status hearing is set for September
15th with a possible trial in the coming
months.